Good morning, everyone. Whoo! Good morning.
Welcome to React Conf 2018. My name is
Tom Occhino. I'm the engineering director
of the React Group at Facebook. I'm
really excited to be here. I'm actually
really excited to talk to people from
all over the country and actually all
over the world. And I know joining us on
the live stream, we have people from all
over the place. So thank you for being
here with us. Before we get started just
a couple of quick logistics. If you
haven't read the Code of Conduct yet,
please do so. It's posted by registration.
It's posted on the website. Follow it. If
you have any issues, please reach out to
me or anyone on the staff. The staff is
all wearing purple shirts. Uh, we got a great
lineup of talks. They're gonna be in this
room today and tomorrow. But if you need
anything else if, uh, if you need to just get
away, if you need to make a phone call, we
have room set up actually directly
behind me. The breakfast room is
available. And in the hallway here, we're
gonna have the fiber arts circle
knitting track with Jen Lucas, so check
that out as well. If you want to get away
from the talks. Uh, lastly there's gonna be, uh,
more updates throughout the day, we'll
have lunch at noon. But before the rest
of the the talks here, I just wanted to
give a big thank you to the organizers. Uh,
putting this on is a lot of work. We were
a little worried that we weren't gonna
be able to put it on this year because
it is so much work. But we found the
organizers of React Rally, ng-conf
Jamieson, uh, Matt and and Joe and then Zero
Slope Events really helped us get this, uh,
put together this year. And I'm really
really happy that we were able to do it.
Thank you all for being here. The first
talk is is our keynote talk with Sophie
Alpert and Dan Abramov. Uh, we're all really
looking forward to this. I'm gonna invite
Sophie up first to kick things off for
us, thanks.
[Applause]
Good morning. see ... ya ... there ... Uh, hello everyone,
welcome to React Conf. I'm really excited
to be here. I'm really excited for the
stuff that we have to announce, uh, for you
this week. Um, my name is Sophie Alpert at
sophiebits on the Internet.
I manage the React core team at Facebook.
By any better that you use React is
doing great.
Our npm downloads are up 70%
year-over-year. The Chrome Dev Tools
extension for React Dev Tools has been
installed by one and a quarter million
developers. And I can show you this list
of companies that's using React. Although
at this point, it's so long, it's kind of
hard to tell how much it changes each
year. For another point of data, we can
look at Google Trends, which shows web
search traffic. So it searches for React
continue to go up. Hopefully that means
more people are using React not that
it's getting more confusing. [Laughing] Um, but, uh, for a
point of comparison, we can look at, um,
jQuery which we have just passed for the
first time in history. [Cheer & Applause]
But this also shows that we have a lot
more room to grow. Um, I was procrastinating
when I was writing this talk. So I was
curious to see what else React is more
popular than. Oops. [Laughing]
Spoiled my joke. Um, but React is more
popular ,I found out, than renewable
energy. [Laughing] It's also more popular than
orange juice. [Laughing] Just think about how common
orange juice is ,right. And not only that
it's more popular than renewable energy
and orange juice put together. So I think
we have a lot to be proud of. But, um, but
enough about these numbers, uh, what I really
like to talk about today is our mission
with React.
Um, ever since React was released in 2013,
our overarching goal,
our primary mission has been to make it
easier to build great UIs. And so when
we're adding new features, we always try
to be very deliberate. We want to
consider a bunch of things when deciding
whether to add a new API. If it makes it
possible to do something you couldn't do
before. If it can dramatically simplify
the code around React in your components
and libraries so that you all have less
work to do and users have less code to
download, that's a win. Or if it helps
encourage best practices like code
splitting,  if we make it easier to code
split your app into multiple bundles,
then our hope is that your apps will end
up being faster. So that's why we add
things like React.lazy which we
announced two days ago. You might have
seen it. But thinking about this mission,
make it easier to great ... to build great
UIs.
There are a lot of different ways that
we approach this. One way we do this is
trying to simplify things that are hard.
If you saw Dan Abramov's talk from
JS Conf Iceland, then you saw a sneak
peek at "Suspense",  which is our idea about
how to dramatically simplify what's
required to do data fetching, code
splitting and any kind of async data
dependencies in your app. Now another way
we try to improve React is by focusing
on performance. If your app runs faster,
your users are going to enjoy using it
more. Conversely, if your
app is laggy, if your app is junky,  then
there your users aren't gonna have a
great time. So we try to spend time on
making React itself faster, because if
React is faster out of the box, you all
need to spend less time optimizing your
own code. One recent performance related
effort that Dan also talked about in
Iceland, as what we call "Time Slicing".
Uh, this is going to let you make sure that
the most important renders in your app
are processed first, in order to unblock
the main thread and make your apps
faster. And a third angle that we
approach our mission from is Developer
tooling to help you debug and understand
your app. From the start,
React has included developer friendly
warnings to help, uh, point out problems
before you might otherwise notice them.
And we've had the React Dev Tools
extension which lets you inspect and
debug your component trees. And in React
16.5, we introduced a new Profiler. It's a
second ... (I don't know what's up with this
clicker)... A second tab their, profiler tab
that helps you understand what's
happening in your app and optimize it. So
Suspense, Time Slicing and the Profiler
are three of the new features that we've
been working on over the last year. We're
really excited to tell you more about
them. But that's actually not what I'm
here to talk about. You're gonna have to
wait till Andrew and Brian's talk
tomorrow morning to hear about that.
Today I want to take a step back and
focus on something else.
What I like to ask is what in React
still sucks. And I have three problems
that I would like to talk through. The
first one is reusing logic between
multiple components. In React our main
building block for our applications is a
component, and components form the
foundation of the two main patterns for
sharing code in React apps between
components which are Higher-order
components and Render props. Both of
these patterns are great for some cases,
but they also come with a significant
downside. You need to restructure your
app anytime you want to pull one of
these in in more complicated examples.
This leads to what I call wrapper hell.
Uh, most of us have seen component trees
that look something like this. [Screaming & Laughing]
And the the nesting you end up with
makes it difficult to follow the data
flow through the app. It would be really
nice if there was some way to reuse this
sort of stateful logic without needing
to change the component hierarchy, right.
The second problem I would like to talk
about is giant components whose logic is
just sort of a tangled mess. When you
look at a thousand line React component
chances are the logic is going to be
split across a lot of different
lifecycle methods in a way that's pretty
difficult to follow. Let's look at an
example. Let's say we have a class
component, and in its component did mount
method it does a few different things: it
subscribes to a datastore, it sends off a
network requests and it starts a timer.
Well, if we look at the component will
unmount method, then we're going to see
basically the exact three opposite
things: it needs to unsubscribe from the
store, it needs to cancel that network
request and it needs to stop the timers.
And when it comes to implementing
component did update, the logic tends to
get even trickier because you need to
compare the old and new props and (ur, and
and) also mirror it again the same tasks
that you have in your other lifecycle
methods. Uh, in this example, each call here
is just one line so this is actually a
lot simpler than what you normally see
in your components. In real-world
components you often end up with an even
more tangled mess, because each (ur, each)
individual task has to be split across
different lifecycle methods, that makes
it hard to tell if, for instance, you
forgot to clean up one of the resources
when you're unmounting your component.
It's pretty hard to see that from the
code. And the third thing that sucks is
the class, ur, understanding classes in
JavaScript can be pretty tricky, and
today we require you to use class
components in order to access state and
lifecycles. If you've ever taken a
function component and converted it to a
class to add some state, you know that
there's a fair amount of boilerplate
that's required in order to just define
a class component. Most beginners and
many experienced devs also tell us that
the way binding and this work in classes
is pretty confusing. It's annoying to
have to think about. And we also
frequently hear that people don't
exactly
know when to use function components
partly because there's always this fear
that you're gonna have to convert it to
a class later anyway. And so you're like
should I ,should I do it now? I don't know.
And so I claim classes are hard for
humans,  uh, but it's not just humans,  I claim
the classes are also hard for machines.
If you ever looked at a minified
component file, you'll see that all the
method names are still unminified. And that if
you have a method that's completely
unused, it doesn't get stripped out.
That's because it's hard to tell at
compile time
exactly how all the methods fit together.
We also found that classes make it
difficult for us to implement hot
reloading reliably. And finally when we
were prototyping an optimizing compiler
to improve the performance of React
components, we found that classes can
encourage some patterns that make it a
lot harder for compilers to optimize.  So
here are the three problems that we have:
reusing logic, giant components, and (ur, and)
classes. So reusing logic because you
often end up with this wrapper hell.
Giant components because you have the
logic split across different lifecycles.
And classes which are difficult for both
humans and machines. So we think we have
a solution that can help with all three
of these. We're really excited to share
it with you to tell you more about it. I
want to welcome up Dan Abramov.
[Applause]
hi my name is Dan I work on the react
team and this is my first time in three
homes and so Sophie talked about these
problems that I think most of you have
encountered in react development and of
course we could approach these problems
one by one so we could try to solve them
in isolation but it seems like solving
one of them makes some other one worse
so for example if we try to solve the
rapper hell by putting more logic into
components themselves then our
components become larger and harder to
refactor and then on the other hand if
we try to split the components apart
into smaller pieces and reuse those then
we end up with more nests than in the
component tree and we get the rapper
hell again and finally in either case we
have all the confusion that comes with
the classes so we think that this is
because these are not three separate
problems we think that this is these are
three symptoms of one problem and the
problem is that react does not provide a
simpler smaller lightweight primitive to
add state or lifecycle than a class
component and so once you add a class
component you can split it up further
without introducing the rapper helm and
in fact it's not a new problem so if you
use react for like more than a couple of
years you might remember then when react
came out it actually included a solution
to this problem it was make sense so
mix-ins allows you to reuse some methods
between classes and this way you
wouldn't have all these rappers so
should we add mix ends back to react
that's right no no we're not gonna do
that I mean the codes usually make sense
the rounds it's not like it's not broken
but we don't encourage using mix-ins and
react and if you curious why there is a
blog post that we wrote code called
mix-ins considered harmful on the react
log where we explain that we think in
our experience the problems that mix-ins
create are worse than the problems that
they solve so that's why we don't
encourage using mix-ins so perhaps we
could just can't solve this problem
maybe its inherent to the react
component model maybe we should just
accept it oh maybe in there is a perhaps
there is a different way we could write
our components that doesn't suffer from
either of these problems and that's what
I'm going to talk about today but before
I start I want to touch a little bit on
the way we approach making changes and
additions to react which is a year ago
we set up an RFC process so RFC stands
for request for comments and it means
that whenever we want to make or
somebody else wants to make a
substantial change or addition to react
they need to write up a proposal with
detail in the motivation and the
detailed design of how this will work
and so that's what we're going to do
we're excited to announce that we are
ready to present a proposal for how we
can solve these three problems
and importantly this proposal does not
have breaking changes or deprecations in
it it is strictly additive it is opt-in
and it adds some new api's which happens
when they try to solve problems and we
would love to hear your feedback on this
proposal which is why we're we're going
to publish it today and we thought about
many ways we could share this proposal
so maybe we just like right off in there
write up an RFC and post it but since we
were going to run react Kampf anyway we
just decided to to show it here and
we're going to demo
[Applause]
don't worry Damaris the displays sorry
technical glitch
can somebody who understands projectors
help me can I make it mirror my desktop
please
yeah
okay but it doesn't show on the screen I
don't see anything
that's that's the problem that I had
okay disaster averted
alright um let me check the font size a
little bit you see it fell all right
so here is a simple react component that
just it is a row this is just some
styling and it it renders a person's
name and so let's say that we want this
name to be editable so how do you do it
in react normally well like if we want
to add an input there we need to return
this component into a class add some
local state to it and let that state
drive the input so that's exactly what
I'm going to do that's what we do today
so I'm gonna do the expert default class
greeting extense react component and so
I'm going to use only stable JavaScript
syntax so constructor props super props
there is the state going to initialize
name to Mary here and I'm going to
declare a random method and copy and
paste this
sorry
okay and so I want this to be instead of
just rendering the name I want the
surrender and input so I'm replacing
this by an input and the value of the
input is this that state that name and
if I make a change I want to call this
dot handle name change that's going to
be my change color and I'm going to
declare it here when the name changes we
call says state like we normally do and
we set the name to eat at target dot
value right so now if I edit the okay so
I I need to bind sorry I need to find
the events on there okay so now I can
actually edit it and it works so a
familiar class component is if you work
with reactive properly right a lot of
those but let's take a step back what if
we didn't have to write a class when we
wanted to use state so I'm not sure how
that's gonna work but I'll just start
with what I know I want to render an
input so I'm gonna put an input here and
the input has a valley and that Valley
is the current name so I'll just pass
name I don't know where to get name from
so it doesn't come from props
I'll just declare it and I don't know
I'll fill it in later it's gonna have a
change down there as well so I'm going
to declare unchanged handle name change
and I'm adding a function here takes an
event and then here I want to tell react
to set the name to something but again
I'm not sure how to do that from a
functional component so I'll just call
something called set name
with the current input value and I'll
just declare it here
all right so these two things they're
closely related right so one of them is
the current value of the name state
variable and the other is a function
that lets us set the name state variable
and so because these things are closely
related I'm actually going to put them
together as a pair of valleys so I'm
going to get them together from
somewhere so where do I get them from
from react local state so how do I use
react local state from a function
component well what if I could just use
state
and past the initial state to specify it
let's see if this works yeah it works
[Applause]
so let's let's compare the two
approaches so on the Left we have a
familiar class component this state has
to be an object we bind some event
handlers so that we can access this
inside the event handler for this that's
a state when we call says state it
actually doesn't just set the state that
merges the state are the argument into
the state object and then when we want
to access the state which it is that
state and that's something so in the
example on the right we don't need to
access this that stayed at something
because the name state variable is
already available in the function it's
just the variable and similarly when we
need to set the state we don't need to
access this that's something because the
function that lets has said the name is
also available in the scope so what is
use state exactly your state is a hook a
hook is a function provided by react
that lets you hook into react features
from your function components and you
state is the first hook that we're going
to take a look at today but there are a
few more so we're going to see them
later
all right so let's go back to our
Familia a class example so let's say we
wanted to add a second field for example
for a surname so the way we normally do
this is we add another key to the state
and we I'm going to copy and paste this
row it's gonna say surname now it's
going to render a surname and handle
surname change when I copy and paste
this event handler this will be surname
and I need to bind it
okay MARY POPPINS so we can see that it
works so how do we do the same with
hooks so one thing we could do is we
could make our state an object as you
can see that the state with hooks state
doesn't have to be an object it can be
any primitive we could make it an object
if we wanted to but we also don't have
to so conceptually surname is is not
closely related to state to the name so
what we could do is we could declare a
second state variable by calling the you
state hook again
so all declare surname I can give it any
name it's just the variable in my code
and sets her name callin you state and
passing the initial state for that state
variable poppins
so again government gonna copy and paste
the row say username the valet surname
handle surname change and when the user
edits the surname not sir name we want
to set the surname
let's see if this works
yay it looks like it works
so we can see that we can use hooks more
than once in a component let's compare
the two approaches in more detail so on
the Left familiar class component state
is always an object has multiple fields
McCall says state will merge some
something into that object and then when
we want to access it we do this that
state that something on the right in the
example using hooks we use the state
hook twice and that declares two state
variables name and surname and whenever
we call set name or set surname
this tells react that it needs to
rerender this component just like if we
called says state and so the next time
reactor renders our components is going
to pass the current name and the current
surname to our component and then we can
use it directly without accessing these
that state that something
all right so let's go back to our class
example what else what other features of
reactor we know so another thing you
might want to do from a component is to
read context so context in case you're
not familiar it's like kind of like
global variables for a subtree so it's
useful for things like read the current
theme like visual theme or the current
language that the user is using and it's
useful to avoid passing everything
through props if you need all components
to be able to read some value so we're
going to import theme context and local
context which I already declared in
another file and the API you've probably
most familiar with for consuming context
especially if you have to consume
multiple contexts is the render crop API
and it looks like this so I'm going to
scroll down here so we can choose theme
context consumer that gives us the theme
in my case it's just going to be a CSS
class so I copy this all this code
inside the render prop and I'm going to
use class name equals theme all right
very old-timey
and I also want to show the current
language so I'm going to use local
context consumer and it's going to
render another role so I will copy and
paste this role can say language
language and render it here okay we can
see that context works and that's
probably normally consume context we
actually added a more convenient API for
accessing it even classes in 1606 but
this is how you can see multiple
contexts so let's look at the at how we
could do this with hooks so as we said
that state is a fundamental feature of
react and this is why you can use state
and so if we want to use context I need
to import my contexts so this is gonna
be a themed context local context and
now if I want to use context from my
component I can use context and then to
get the current theme I can use context
same context and to get the current
locale I can use context local context
and this doesn't just read the context
it also subscribes the component to
updates to this context but it just
gives me the current values so I can I
can put it into my CSS class name and I
can add the bro first language and I can
put it here
[Applause]
all right so let's let's compare the two
approaches so this is the traditional
kind of render prop API
it is very explicit about what it's
doing but it does get a little bit
nested and you encounter this not just
with context with with any kind of
render properly API so with hooks it
does the same thing but it's flat so we
just say we use this context in this
context and we get the theme and locale
and then we can use them so you might be
wondering at this point how can react
possibly know for example I have this to
you state calls so how does it know
which state variable corresponds to
which you state call and the answer is
that react relies on the order of these
calls this may be a little bit unusual
and in order for this to work correctly
there is a rule that you need to follow
when you use cooks and the rule is that
you cannot call hook inside a condition
it has to be at the top level of your
component so if I do something like if
props condition and then I call the you
state hook here we actually have a
linter plugin that is going to complain
that this is not the correct way to use
hooks and we realize that this is an
unusual limitation but it is pretty
important for hooks tour correctly and
also to enable certain things that I
think will you will like that our so a
bit later
all right so let's go back to our class
so the other thing you might want to
reach for the class for is lifecycle
methods so the most commonly use case
for lifecycle methods is you want to
perform some side effect such as firing
off request performing some kind of
imperative Dom mutation interfacing with
the browser api's so you might want to
do something like this and you can't do
during rendering because it's it's not
rendered yet so the way you do
side-effects and react is you declare a
life cycle method like component amount
and then let's say that if let me show
this so you see at the top of the screen
it says react up so there is actually a
browser API that lets us update this so
let's say we want the tab title to be
the name of the person and changed it as
I type and so to set it initially I'm
going there is a browser you got to do
this is documented title equals this
that state that name was space was this
the state that's her name so now we can
see it's as Mary Poppins but then if I
if I edit it it doesn't get
automatically updated because I also
need to implement component it update
for the for the side effects to be
consistent with what I rendered so I'm
going to declare a component it update
and just copy and paste this all right
so now says Mary Poppins but if I
started editing it the document title
updates and this is how we perform side
effects in a class
so how do we do this with hooks well the
ability to perform side effects is
another core feature of react components
so if we want to use an effect from our
component make an import use effect from
react and then we want to tell react
what to do after react has flushed our
components to the Dom so we pass a
function which is where we perform our
effect so I'm going to say document the
title equals name plus space plus
surname you can see it says Mary Poppins
here and if I start editing it actually
updates
so what default use effect runs both
after the initial render and after every
update so by default it is consistent
with what he rendered and you can opt
out of this behavior if like for
performance reasons and/or if you have
special logic and reinstall after me
will touch a little bit on this so let's
compare DG approaches so in the in the
class we divide method we divide the
logic based on lifecycle method names so
this is why we have component amount
component it update they fire at
different times and we sometimes repeat
some logic between them we could extract
it to a function but still we would have
to call it in two places and remember to
keep it consistent and with with the
effect hook the effects are consistent
by default although there is a way to
opt out of that and not is that in the
class we need to access this that state
so there needs to be a special API to do
this but in the effect example we
actually don't need a special API to
access the state
variable because it's already in the
scope of the function it is declared
right above and this is why the effect
is declared inside the component rather
than the rather than outside because
this gives us access to state variables
ability to set them and anything else
like the current context value for
example or any of these contexts all
right so let's go back to the familiar
class example another thing you might
want to use life cycle methods for in a
class is subscriptions so maybe you want
to subscribe to some kind of browser API
and it gives you some value for example
the window size and you want to update
the state in response to changes to this
value and so the way we could do this in
a class let's say that we want to that
we want to monitor the window width so
I'm going to put with interstate this
window in there with browser API and I
want to render it let me copy and paste
this so this is gonna say width and I'm
going to render it here it is that state
that width this is the width of the
window not with of Mary Poppins
and I'm going to add a I'm going to add
in event listener so we need to actually
listen to changes in the width so at
window that event add event listener
I'll I'm going to listen to the resize
event handle resize and I need to
declare this event and so this is where
we're going to update the with state to
be window that inner width and we need
to bind it and and I also need to
unsubscribe so I don't want a memory
leak with like keeping these
subscriptions I want to unsubscribe from
this event so the way we do this in a
class is we create another life cycle
method called component will unmount and
I'm going to copy and paste this logic
here except this will be a remove event
listener so we set up in the event
listener and we remove the event
listener and we can verify that this
actually works by dragging this you see
the width is changing so it works so
let's see how could how we could do this
with hooks so conceptually listening to
the window width has nothing to do with
setting the document title so that's why
we're not gonna put it in that effect
it's conceptually completely separate
effect and just like we could use state
more than once to declare multiple state
variables we can use effect more than
once to perform different side effects
so I want to subscribe to window add
event listener resize handle resize and
I'm gonna need to keep some state for
the current width
so I'm actually going to declare another
state variable so I'll say with and sat
with we get them by using state with
window inner with as the initial valium
and now in my handle resize function
I'll just declare it here because it
isn't used anywhere else and it's going
to set with tree to the current with I
mean I need to render it so I'll copy
and paste this row I'm gonna say width
and finally I need to clean up after
this effect so I need to specify how to
clean up and again conceptually cleaning
up is part of this effect so this effect
has a cleaner place and the order you
the way you can specify it is that any
effect can optionally return a function
and if it does return the function then
react will call this function to clean
up after the effect so this is where we
unsubscribe
okay let's just verify that this
actually works yay so let's compare the
two approaches on the Left we have a
familiar class component nothing
surprising there we we have some side
effects some related logic is split
apart so we can see that document title
has been set here but it's also being
set here and then we subscribe to an
effect here
sorry subscribe to the event here but we
unsubscribe here so these things need to
be in sync with each other and then this
method contains two unrelated methods
two unrelated lines so that me in the in
feature make it a bit difficult to test
them in isolation but it looks very
familiar so that's this nice so this
code probably looks less familiar but
let's take another look at what's going
on here in with hooks we separate code
not based on the life cycle method name
but based on what the code is doing so
we can see that there is one effect
which is we updated document title
that's one thing this component can do
and then there is another effect which
is subscribing tree to the window resize
event and update in the state when it
changes and this effect has a cleanup
phase which means that when it's time to
remove this effect react removes it and
avoids the memory leaks and if you've
been carefully watching you might notice
that since effect run after every render
we're just gonna keep resub scribing so
there is a way to optimize this so
default is to be consistent which is
important if you for example use some
prop here I need to resupply tea from
props or something similar but there is
a way to optimize it and opt out of this
behavior and Brian in the
stock will mention how to do it alright
so there is one more thing that I want
to show here so this component is
getting pretty large and it's fine so we
expect that since you now can do more in
function components they will get larger
and that's totally okay but you might
want to reuse some of that logic in
other components or extract it or test
it separately what's interesting though
is that hope calls they are just
function calls and components they are
just functions so how do you share your
logic between two functions you extract
it to a different function that's what
I'm going to do you're going to copy and
paste this and I'm going to create a new
function called use window with and I'll
just paste it here and so we need the
width in our component in order to
render it so I need to return it from
this function which is the current width
and then I can go back up and I can say
Const width equals use window width
[Applause]
[Music]
so what is this function we didn't do
anything special we just extracted the
function but there is a convention here
so we are calling this function a custom
hook and by convention custom hook names
always start with use and so there are
two reasons for this we're now going to
like read your function name or to
string it or anything like this but it
is an important convention because first
of all this lets us lint automatically
for violation of the first rule that I
described about : hooks unconditionally
so if we didn't know if something is a
hook then we wouldn't be able to do that
and another reason is that if you just
look at the component code you kind of
want to know if some function can have
some state inside of it so it's
important that there is a convention is
he okay use something it means that it's
potentially stateful and here with gives
us the current bits and subscribes us to
updates through it so if we wanted to we
could even go further it's probably not
necessary in this example but I just
want to give you like a sense of water
you could do so let's say like maybe
setting the document title was a bit
more complicated and you wanted to like
extract it or test it separately so I
could just copy and paste this and I
could write a new custom hook I'm gonna
call this one use document title and so
the name and surname don't really make
sense in the Scopes context we just want
to call this title and this is going to
be an argument so custom hooks are
JavaScript functions so they can take
arguments and return values or not
return so it is going to take title as
an argument and now in my component I
can say use document title name plus
surname
in fact I could go even further so in
this case it's totally unnecessary but
again maybe our inputs were more
complicated maybe we were tracking
whether the input was focused and
blurred whether it has been validated
submitted and so on so maybe we had some
more logic there we wanted to pull it
out of our components and reduce
duplication and there is already some
duplication so we have this like almost
identical event handlers so what if we
could just I'm going to delete one of
them and extract the other one I'm going
to create a new hook that I'm going to
call use form input so this is my change
handler now I'll also copy and paste
this declaration so this defines the
state for this input and so it's no
longer name and set name I'll just color
generically Valley and set value it's
going to take the initial value as an
argument and this is just going to be a
handle change and this will set value so
what do we want to get in order to use
this user input and our component we
want to get the current value and a
change candor these are the things that
we attach to the input so let's just
return them return value and unchanged
handle change so now if we go back up we
can say name equals use form input meri
the name is going to be an object with
valley and non change fields and surname
is use form input Poppins so this is now
going to be named at Valley and surnamed
at Valley because this is where the
string is and so now I can remove this
and I can spread over the name object
someone is laughing alright let's just
verify it and break it yeah it works so
each time we poll a hook its state is
completely isolated and this is because
we just rely on the order of who calls
and not on names or anything so you can
call the same hook multiple times each
call will get its own local state so
let's compare the three approaches for
the last time so on the Left we have a
familiar class component it has some
some state in an object bind some
methods has some logic spread across
different life cycle methods it has a
bunch of event handlers uses uses
something things from the context and
render stuff pretty familiar and on the
right pane this may not look like the
react components were used to but it
kind of makes sense even if you don't
know how these functions are implemented
you can see okay it uses to form inputs
uses some context to get theme and
locale it uses the window width and
document title and it renders a bunch of
stuff and if we want to we can scroll
further and we can see okay so this is
how the input works this is how setting
the document title works this is how the
window with suppression works or maybe
this could be an NPM package and you
don't actually need to know that all we
could pull it back into a component or
copy and paste between components so
hooks give you custom hooks give you the
flexibility to create your own
abstractions that are not they do not
inflate your react componentry and avoid
the wrapper hell
[Applause]
[Music]
and importantly these are not two
separate applications so this is
actually one application so I have this
window open just to demonstrate that
classes can work side by side with hooks
and while hooks represent our vision for
the future of react we don't want to
make breaking changes like this so we
need to keep classes working let's go
back to you the slides all right now
this is a slider you can actually tweet
we present the Hookes proposal to you
today
Hookes led to use all react features
without having to write a class they do
not deprecated classes but you have the
option to not have to write them we
intend to cover all use cases for
classes with hooks as soon as possible
there are a few that are missing but
we're working on them and hooks lets you
reuse stateful logic extracted out of
components tested separately reuse it
between different components without
introducing the wrapper hell and again
importantly it's not a breaking change
completely backwards compatible strictly
addition additive and you can find the
we wrote the documentation for hooks so
you can find it at this year around and
we want to hear from you the react
immune to you when I hear what you think
about hooks whether you like them or not
and we realize that it's pretty hard to
give feedback without actually trying
them so we built them and we released
sixty sixty and seven alpha it's not a
major release it's a minor release but
in alpha where you can try hooks and
we've been trying them in production at
Facebook for about a month so we don't
expect major bugs there but the api's
themselves may change together with your
feedback and I asked you not to rewrite
anything like not to rewrite their whole
apps and hooks because first of all it's
it's a proposal and second because
personally I I find that it takes a bit
of a mind shift to start thinking in
hooks and it might be a bit confusing if
you try to just take a class component
and convert it but I do encourage you to
try using hooks in some of the newer
code that you write in and let us know
what you think so
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
so in our view hooks represent our
vision for the future of reactive but I
think they also represent the way we
move react forward and that is we don't
do big rewrite we want the new patterns
that we like better to coexist with the
old patterns so that we can have gradual
migration and adoption just like you can
gradually adopt react itself and this is
almost the end of my talk I want to end
it on a personal note so I started
learning react about four years ago and
one of my first questions was why JSX
but my second one of the next questions
was I can figure out what does the logo
have to do with react so the project is
not called Adam it's not a physics
engine
so one interpretation is that it's kind
of upon on
reactions so atoms participate in
chemical reactions reactions react but
it's not a flame with react actually
Gotti I found a different interpretation
that made more sense to me and the way I
think about it
we know that physical matter consists of
atoms and we've learned that it's the
types of these atoms and their
properties that determine how the
physical matter looks and behaves and
react has taught me something similar
that you can take a user interface and
you can split it into these independent
units called components and it's the
types and properties of these components
that can describe how the user interface
looks and behaves
what's ironic though is that the word
Adam it literally means indivisible so
when scientists just discovered Adam for
the first time they thought this is the
smallest thing we're gonna find but
later they discovered an electron which
is a smaller particle inside the atom
and it turned out it actually electrons
explain a lot about how atoms work and I
kind of feel the same way about hooks I
don't feel like hooks are a new feature
rather I feel that hooks provide me with
access to react features that I already
know such as state and context and life
cycle and I feel like hooks are a more
direct representation of react and that
they really explain how a component
works inside and I feel like they've
been hiding in plain sight for four
years and in fact if you look at the
react go go you can see those electron
orbits there so maybe hooks have been
there all along thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
damn thank you so much Sophie thank you
as well a couple years ago one of the
things we said at the original react
Kampf was that we we felt like we found
a better model for our the front end of
our applications and that the atomic
unit it used to be you know you had
views and you had models and controllers
and we thought that the component was a
better kind of primitive for that and I
think we're really excited that we hope
that hooks will make our applications
even more maintainable going forward our
next presenter if you use a router in
your react application he is almost
certainly either partially or completely
responsible for that probably needs no
further introduction welcome Ryan
Florence
[Applause]
[Music]
I'm having the same technical
difficulties dan did something good
company are you feeling a little bit
like when you first saw JSX
better okay
I was I was honestly not quite sure how
people were going to respond to it so my
talk is 90% cleaner with react hooks I
used you might know me from react router
I used to work at react training but now
I'm running reached at Tech where I'm
trying to make react accessible for the
developers and their users so I've got
open source their workshops online
courses and stuff take a look and then
also give me a follow on on twitter dan
just said don't rewrite your apps in
hooks I think you should
we're just gonna we're just gonna dig in
we're gonna do a bunch of code here and
see how hooks feel in a little bit more
real-world use case so this is this is
kind of this is the state of react today
right we got these render props and they
get all nested I've loved these things
since I saw them at react Europe when
Cheng Liu showed us react motion but I
have not loved the syntax disaster is
what I started calling this render props
big trade-off is that syntax disaster
Dan and Sophie covered really well a lot
of the problems that hooks solve with
this so I won't go into any more detail
except one other thing is something
that's always bothered me about these
render props is it gives a false
hierarchy here I've got two media
listeners where I'm listening to the
media query and so I can see if this
thing matches that those two queries and
it looks like there's a hierarchy here
but there's actually not so let's let's
see how this code feels when we switch
it over to hooks here's how it's all
implemented we've got some initial state
here we set up when the component mounts
we do a quick check here because between
initialization or a construction and
mounting our screen size could have
changed especially with suspense coming
so we set some state just in case it
changed create a listener add the
listener and then we add removed
listener to our component instance then
we've got a component did update we do a
little dip here because if our query
changes we want to reset up this
listener Reese absque Ribe to it and we
need to clean it up as well and then
when we unmount we clean it all up and
of course we yield out that state or
call back with that state with the
render prop so let's come to the app and
and switch this up instead let's say
yeah I'm gonna use let there haven't
been enough like semicolon conversations
lately so I figured
we can start some more of those kinds of
conversations and my screen size is kind
of small and I'm getting old and typing
five characters is you know I'm pushing
I'm getting close to 40 I'd rather just
type three characters but anyway we're
going to use media here let's grab this
out drop it in there and then we're
gonna have a large same thing use media
grab this put it up here I got some
extra quotes now and then we just get to
delete stuff yeah so many little Woo's
out there everyone is pumped about this
let's go let's go implement it so let's
make use media work so we're going to
say function use media and we get the
query in as an argument and then up top
we're going to have our we're gonna have
our state so we're just gonna slide all
this code around and see where it moves
so our state comes in like this and then
we'll say let matches equal use state
and we put in that initial state there
and of course we need that second part
of the return of set matches so that's
why our state goes component did mount
we just call setup so there's really
nothing to do there but we will use an
effect here you can think of use effect
as component did mount and a few other
things but for now just component did
now so when we mount we grab all of this
stuff and run it so we're going to move
all of that into the effect and in here
we're no longer reading this dot props
like query SEM it's that one as well
we're actually just reading an argument
that comes into a function it's funny
because we've said that about react for
a long time right think of props like
arguments to a function or what the
hooked it is an argument to a function
we're not going to read from this state
matches we're just gonna read from
matches cuz we already got it right up
here
and then we're not gonna call set state
we're going to call actually let's reuse
as much code as possible set matches
it's important to be efficient no matter
what task you're doing don't want to
waste CPU cycles up here and we've got
our listener we don't call set state
let's try that again set matches I
practiced last night doing that and then
we add the listener and this this not
just this but this this is kind of
difficult as we've seen you all know
that so I don't need to spend any time
talking about that so with a hook
instead of having to track this this
function across our instance we just get
to hand that over to react so you know
what I don't care when that's supposed
to be cleaned up you figure that out
okay so now we've got our component did
mount in their component did update so
this is interesting when we update we
dip the prop and see if we should remove
the listener and then setup again do we
get like previous
previous art now where do I do it
there's a second argument here the
second argument we tell react what stuff
matters
about this hook so I just tell it well
that's almost it i say hey the query
matters here
some of you were looking at this
thinking I liked hooks until now this is
the moment
no wonder Dan didn't want to cover that
part well let Ryan do it he bombed
reactor alley so he can all right so
this is a whole lot like component did
update as well so react is gonna do that
diff for us so before you get too grumpy
about this API you know and you're
probably thinking like oh I don't they
passed the arguments back into us
don't don't think of it that way don't
think of it as these are arguments that
I used in here think about a div and if
you put will do the innerhtml
maybe we did we put the inner or the
query as the HTML of the div we don't
think about this but react is diffing
that query I mean not really it dips the
react elements and it does the
reconciliation but conceptually we can
think react looks at that Korean goes oh
that's different now I'm going to go do
some Dom node or a Dom node I guess it's
the the Twitter egg and we could change
the inner HTML to something new right
it's gonna go do an effect based on when
that query changes so don't don't get
too grumpy about this thing we're just
we're just letting react do it now I
mean we had to dip it anyway and I can't
tell you how many bugs there are in my
workshops where people forget to diff
the prog in component did update and
then set things up again so react is now
going to handle this diff for us and it
will actually remove the listener for us
and then it will also set everything
back up goodbye component did update
all right component will unmount well
yeah also if the core you changes will
unsubscribe and if the component unmount
it'll do that so all that's left is our
return and then we return matches let's
save it double check our work looks like
it works
[Applause]
90% cleaner let's see I mean even like
I've got prettier set to like 52 columns
or something like that and it just it's
just kind of like you look at this thing
Ike's close your eyes if this makes you
dizzy and now it's all just I'm in so
cleaned up I don't really like talking
about clean code I like code that works
I don't usually care how clean it is but
I love it when you get an abstraction
that actually helps you write code that
you don't sort of feel bad about when
you deploy it I'm gonna I'm gonna put
this back to the to the old way so we'll
look at it again later
let's look in a little bit more
real-world example and what better way
to talk about the real world than to
look at pictures of the galaxy actually
it's not our galaxy these are these are
pictures from the Hubble Space Telescope
we're gonna build a carousel so I went
and did some research on how to build an
accessible carousel for people using the
mouse screen readers keyboard navigation
and all that kind of stuff so we're
gonna we're gonna do full-blown carousel
here we're not going to do any half
stuff or show Mary Poppins window width
that's a little creepy if you're
tracking that Dan okay so here is here's
our app let me bump up the font a bit
I've got a current index if I switch
this index you'll notice that the slide
changes back there we've got some the
slide nav is right there here are the
slide controls this bar down here is
actually a progress bar we're gonna
animate this thing that's what we know
when the next slide is coming and then
when we click these we're also going to
manage focus so we're going to move
focus from the button that we just
clicked to the actual slides so that
someone using a screen reader will be
able to read the text inside the slide
they don't want to just change something
and then not read it so let's let's
bring this thing to life so we're going
to use state here and then we're gonna
have our set current index so this is a
lot like object D structuring it's kind
of new for some people a radies
structuring is in some other language
that's in Ruby that's where I first
learned D structuring but yeah it's just
like object destruction but it's arrays
and it's actually been around longer
than object D structuring and Java is
good
so let's what should we do let's do the
list of the forward and back buttons
first so I'm going to come down here to
our controls play/pause gonna have a
space or gif to have a good app I told
you I was old half of you don't know
what that is but those that do okay what
do we want to do want to say set current
index we're going to go backwards so we
need to do we're going to do current
index minus 1 but we want to cycle
through if we get to the first one we're
going to do a little bit of computer
science here
got from stackoverflow don't trust this
code you you sometimes like you look at
Kodiak that's kind of weird how they did
this but I mean Ryan wrote it so I bet
he knows what he's doing with it
nope so I encourage more comments like
that and then down here what do we do we
say on click we're gonna set current
index here as well but this one's a
little bit easier so we're gonna do
current index plus 1 and then modulus
slice that length so again this is just
so that it'll cycle through let's save
it come over here cool
what should we do next
these slideshows usually automatically
play right so we're not going to be what
I want to do we want to have like an
interval or a set timeout or something
right
but we're going to use effect if we want
to put a clock on this page then that's
an effect that's something we would have
done in component did metal so instead
we do it and use effect here and we will
set timeout I've got a slide duration
already out there and once again we're
going to set current index to our new
index plus 1 I love computer science so
much ok let's save it it's about 3
seconds all right pretty cool
play pause let's let's get the let's get
the play button working we're getting
some more states will say is playing I
mean that could work is play 9 and set
is playing will use some state
we're not playing yet let's come down to
our controls here's playing pause so
I'll say is playing so if we're playing
then let's render the pause button so
when we pause we set is playing
and then when we play we set is playing
to true
wait a sec I said false if is playing
then set timeout it's important like Dan
was talking about you don't do this
outside those effects need to be there
all the time the way to think about that
is you actually really really love hooks
in fact you love them unconditionally
[Applause]
that just that just came to me during
Dan's talk and I'm really glad that
landed hmm I was actually Jared Palmer
told me to get a Captain Hook outfit and
like come up here I'd be like I'm gonna
show you how to program with hooks and
for 30 minutes try to type on my
keyboard then we almost went to the
strip to go get one but that one might
have not been safe for work so we didn't
okay so I am I'm gonna save this so it's
not playing one two three okay now I'm
gonna click the play button one two
three cool I'm gonna click the pause
button I don't know if I when did i
click that so I'm gonna play again okay
now I'm gonna pause so I should stop
play
is is dance still in here I mean I've
only been using these for like ten
minutes
so clear my time out return what all
right here we go
sorry that was staged I want to see if
Dan would actually come up and I know
everyone on the react team is like when
is he gonna pass the second argument to
use effect okay so this this is working
right now but it's it's got all sorts of
problems this is my favorite one so it's
playing and then I click click click
click click click then I'll stop I'll
get one more and now it's done so we've
got to let react know it's got to do
that component did update diff and it's
got to we need to clear this time out
because when I'm when I'm playing and
then I hit pause there's that last
timeout that's still there that hasn't
been cleaned up so that's why we get
that one extra in there so what we need
to do is a first tell react that uh oh
sorry and then the other bug where the
click click click happens is I click
next next next and the timeout doesn't
get cleared and I end up setting
multiple timeouts because the current
index changes and so I get a re render
on every single one so I get a set
timeout on every single one of those so
I'll come in here and I'll tell it if
the current index changes or if is
playing changes then I want you to clean
up my mess so we'll let our timeout
equal that and then we can clear timeout
right there so now as that state changes
over time react knows when when to clean
stuff up so we got one transition I
pause it and then it should be done and
again don't get grumpy
this arguments fine it's just like it's
just like this is playing react is
already doing dips for you it's already
doing that in the reconciler but we're
not rendering elements here so this
stuff can't participate in that kind of
a diff and so when we drop this stuff in
here we're saying okay plug this
affecting to the Reckling reconciler
based on these things just like our just
like our elements the owners I emphasize
that as I was so grumpy about these okay
what's next this progress part let's do
the progress bar this thing is really
fun so down here we've got a progress
bar and we're gonna animate if we're
playing so let's go up to the progress
bar let's see how it works so we've just
got this value here and watch it's gonna
bump up to 75% now we can put it back
down to 50% and then we could also just
use progress and
yeah I mean you know you're not sure if
you want to clap could you have no idea
how it works I think I like it
this is not built-in to react this is
this is my own custom hood isn't that so
cool though it's like I had just a
singular value or a static value and to
refactor to something stateful is just a
function call like it's it's still kind
of blowing my mind I haven't gotten
bored with react I've been teaching it
at workshops for three and a half years
thousands of people maybe a hundred
workshops and I still don't get bored
with it and now there's this stuff and
I'm like a little bit hyper when I talk
about it and I'll tell you what the last
workshops or the last couple weeks have
been impossible to keep my mouth shut
there are a couple people here who are
at some of them and yeah it was I'm like
yeah I know a render props are kind of
weird hire de components are kind of
weird but just wait two weeks
I got a survey result back that was like
I want my money back everything's
changing in two weeks and I was like
okay
like maybe I should not tell them
anything at all it's actually not that
great look didn't reset okay so how do
we get these these effects to reset we
just talked about it's that second
argument right so that react can diff
and change it so our progress bar down
here only knows about time and animate
and then our use progress let's go look
at it
don't worry too much well it's going on
here there's just some
requestanimationframe and calculating
time stamps but it it will reset if anim
and time change I don't want to have to
tell my progress bar all about current
index and is playing if I could pass
that stuff in and then it could pass
that stuff to use progress then it could
pass that to the argument there but
react already has a built-in way with
our elements to reset state whether
you're using hooks or you're using a
class component it's the key so you need
to say if the current index or is
playing changes I want a different
instance of a progress bar and then the
state inside of the hook I mean it
doesn't get reset the thing just goes
away and then you get a brand new one
but you can think about it as this will
reset the state of the progress bar
whenever those two pieces of state
change cool
and now I want to read about the Eagle
Nebula hey I want to read the Eagle
Nebula pillars are bathed in put hey
they ultraviolet light from a grouping
of young
oh my charge me crazy on websites when
like they actually have a carousel that
you actually care about and then it just
keeps on going so how can we fix that
when we click next or previous we could
say set is playing false right and then
we could do the same thing up here on
here set is playing false but the more
state we get in these components you
kind of end up with with this and that's
that's fine but maybe you'd rather do
something a little bit more conventional
where maybe you've got some state to
talk about and maybe you would like to
co-locate all of the management of that
state with something like I don't know
dispatch and to do that maybe you would
like to use a reducer this is actually
built in to react hooks so it comes
comes straight from react we pass it
some initial state so the kering index
is 0 we pass it is playing faults and
then in here I'm just gonna I'm just
gonna write the reducer as quick as I
can
I'm really bad at switch statements
though I didn't use them until Redux
came around I'm still not sure how I
feel about switch statements but uh I
can finally write them without having to
stackoverflow it so we've got case
progress and we've got case next and
these these basically do the same thing
so I'm going to return all my state and
then I'll say is playing if I'm
progressing from slide to slide I want
to keep playing and so I'll say is
playing is action type if I could type
it's progress so it'll keep on playing
but if I click next it won't be playing
anymore and then I'll do the current
index yes or computer science almost
forgot what to do at the end there and
then okay so that's what are we yelling
about we're gonna default case alright
default turn our state I so got next and
progress let's copy this and do previous
and oops we're going to subtract from
their slides length and then is playing
is false and then what else we got we've
got case play so when we play I want to
say is playing true and then we've got
pause and it's playing false one two
three four five alright so that is all
of them I'm gonna delete this stuff and
then we're gonna have some some
disasters right here so let's let's fix
all of these bugs and what else we got
if is playing so what state is playing
almost so we're not gonna set current
index here we're going to dispatch
progress and then down here more putting
state on there what else you got
yes lint what else you got stay current
index we're getting close
we don't set his playing we dispatch a
tight play and then down here same thing
oops this one should be paused I heard
somebody grumble over here thank you
whenever you hear the grumble looks like
you did something wrong but you don't
know what they said just just get
nervous so previous slide won't do all
that anymore we're just dis
batch type is a previous same thing here
we don't have to do that those two
things we just got to say what we're
doing go to next
a couple more bits here not Sophie bits
these are Ryan bits and I got one fan
and then this already covered this
that's a for the screen reader to know
that something's happening okay
as a slight happy try not to make you
dizzy sliding up here I think it's I
think it's happy let's save that
yeah throw this stuff on context you can
fill in the rest of that statement
sorry mark I wrote a blog post called
this suspense is killing redux I might
write another one called Redux gets the
hook but no I I love I love reducers
from redux I love thinking about my
state on one thing I don't think we
talked enough about colocation in the
community and we're seeing it now dan
talked a whole lot about it where we
used to have this kind of stuff spread
all over the place in a component but we
kind of felt like oh but it's all in a
components so it's co-located but we
didn't realize that if we looked a
little bit closer
we had logic spread across our component
and that stuff wasn't co-located so
hooks led us co-locate these effects
colo-colo Kedar state and use reducer it
lets us co-locate the changes to the
state in this component we're almost
done let's uh let's get these things to
work and manage some focus so I'm gonna
come down to those actually that's what
we have a reducer we can actually think
about our app and a little bit higher
level so we could say which would call
this one I'll call it go to because I'm
old enough to know that that's a thing
but young enough to not know what it
really was will have a current index and
that will be on action dot index and so
then we'll come down to our slide nav
here it is
and we'll say on click let's dispatch
type go to index and use my keyboard now
notice the down down here how it's it's
highlighted so I'm using my keyboard to
navigate around and so what we actually
want to do here for a screen reader is
and a keyboard user maybe this slide has
a form in it or something
we actually want to move the focus up to
that element and so we'll know that we
did it right if this isn't doesn't have
that extra circle around it now I got to
say here I've been using hooks a little
bit longer than
the duration of this talk but not much
so I'm not sure what the right way to
model this focus management is with
hooks yet and so don't don't think like
oh wow this is cool that's I'm going to
do it in my apps I think I think we'll
eventually figure out a better way to do
it but for now this is this is just kind
of the first thing that's come to my
mind so I'm gonna have some extra state
here and call it take focus and then in
each one of these actions I'm going to
say take focus faults and then all of
them except for go-to and this one I'm
going to say true so I want to take
focus when we're going to something
specifically and then down here words
are sliding that are our slides
so our slide we can pass in state take
focus and now let's go up to our slide
sorry a little bit of bouncing around so
here's the slide it gets that prop it
also knows if it's the current slide we
throw Tanner Bendix on there so that we
can actually focus it and to focus an
element we need a ref
hmm so with everything we've seen this
morning where do you think we can get a
ref from if we need to use a ref how
might we use a ref yep
and then if we need to focus we use
effect and we want to change the focus
depending on if we're current and if we
should take focus and I'll say if we're
current and we should take focus ref
current focus
notice the circle moves off of there
there we go
[Applause]
[Music]
ninety percent cleaner react thank you
very much
[Applause]
[Music]
Ryan thank you so much I like how you
snuck in - new - new hooks in there -
introduce to everybody we're gonna take
a short break about 20 minutes be back
in here at 11:00 we'll commence with the
the talks but for now I'll have some
coffee if you need to use the restroom
that's good - thank you