嗨。我的名字是 Dan。我在 React
Team 工作，这是我第一次参加 React
大会。 [掌声] 刚才 Sophie 讲述了这三个
问题，我想大多数的开发者在 React
开发过程中都会遇到这些问题。当然，
我们可以逐一来解决
这些问题。我们可以尝试独立地去  one by one, so we could try to solve them
解决这些问题。但是实际上解决其中一个问题
可能会使其他问题更加严重。
比如我们尝试去解决
“包装地狱”的问题，将更多的逻辑放到
组件里面，那么我们的
组件会变得更大，而且更难以
重构。另一个方面，如果
我们尝试将组件拆分为
更小的片段，方便重用，那么
我们的组件树的嵌套更多了，
而且又会以
“包装地狱” 收场。最后，无论那种情况，
使用 class 都会让人产生
困惑。所以我们认为造成这种情况是因为
这不是三个独立的
问题。我们认为，这是一个问题的
三个症状。问题在于
React 没有原生提供一个比 class 组件更
简单，更小型，更轻量级的方式来
添加 state 或 生命周期。
而且一旦你使用了 class
组件，你没有办法在不造成“包装地狱”的情况下,
进一步拆分它。事实上，
这并不是一个新问题。如果你
已经使用了 React 几年，
你也许还记得在 React
刚出来的时候，事实上已经包含了一个解决  came out it actually included a solution
方案。嗯，这个解决方案就是 mixins。
Mixins 能够让你在 class 之间复用
方法，通过这种方法可以
减少嵌套。所以我们要在
React 里面重新添加 mixins 吗？ [对 ... 不...]
对了，不，不，我们不会添加 mixins。
啊，我的意思是之前使用
mixins 的代码并不是无法使用了。
但是我们不再推荐在 React 里使用 mixins。
如果你好奇我们这么做的原因，可以在 React Blog 里面
查看我们之前写的一篇文章，题目是
《 Mixins 是有害的》。
在文章中，根据我们的  Blog, where we explain that we think in
实验结果，我们发现 mixins 带来的问题
远比它解决的问题
多。因此，我们不推荐大家
使用 mixins。那么也许
我们解决不了这个问题了，
因为这是 React 组件模型固有的
问题。也许我们不得不
选择接受现实。 [笑声] 或者也许
有另外一种书写组件的
形式，可以避免
这些问题。这也就是今天
我将要分享的内容。但是在
开始分享我们在 React 的
改动和新特性之前，我想先讲讲
一年前我们建立的
RFC 流程，RFC 表示
request for comments，它意味着
无论是我们还是其他人
想要对 React 做出
大量变化或者添加新特性时,
都需要撰写一个提案，提案里面
需要包含动机的详情和
该提案如何工作的详细设计。
这正是我们要做的事情。
我们非常兴奋地宣布：我们已经
准备好了一个提案
来解决这三个问题。
重要的是，本提案没有
不兼容的变化，也没有弃用任何功能。
本提案是严格添加性的、可选择的
而且增加了一些新的 APIs 来
帮助我们解决这些问题。并且我们
希望听到你们对本提案的反馈，
这也是为什么我们在今天发表本提案
的原因。我们想过很多
发表本提案的方式，
也许我们可以写好提案后，
提出一个 RFC 然后放在那里。 但是既然
我们总是要召开 React 大会，我们决定
在本次大会上发表这个提案。那么，
接下来进入 Demo 环节。
[掌声]
我的屏幕已经投在了显示器上。对不起，
有点技术故障。
呃，有谁会用这个投影仪，来
帮帮我。[笑声] 呃，我能复制我的桌面吗？
请。
(我能) 是啊。 [笑声]
好的，但是屏幕上没有显示，我
什么都看不到。 [笑声]
这就是我现在的问题。 [掌声]
好的，灾难过去了。[笑声]
好的，嗯，让我来稍微调整下
文字大小。你们能看清吗？ [可以的。] 好的。
那么，我们来看，这里是一个普通的 React 组件，
这是一个 Row 组件，这里有一些
样式，然后渲染出一个
人名。我们想要做的是
让这个名字可编辑。那么我们平时在 React 里
通常是怎么做的呢？我们需要
在这里添加一个 input，需要将这些内容放到
class 里面返回，添加一些本地
state，让 state 来
驱动 input。这也是我
准备做的事情。这也是现今大家通常做的事情。
我要 export default class
Greeding extends React component。我也
只会在这里使用稳定的 javaScript
语法。接下来是 constructor props, super props。
在这里把 state 里的 name 初始化为
Mary。接下来我要
声明一个 render 函数，复制一下这段代码然后
粘贴到这里。
对不起。
好的。我希望这里不再
仅仅渲染 name，我希望这里可以渲染一个
input。我把这里替换为
一个 input，然后 input 的值设置为
this.state.name。 然后
在 input 输入发生变化时，调用
this.handleNameChange， 这是我的
change 回调函数。我把它
声明在这里，当名字发生变化时，
像我们通常做的那样调用 setState 方法。然后
将 name 设置为 e.target.value
对吧。如果我编辑 ... [页面上报了 TypeError 的错误] 好吧，所以我
应该去绑定 ... [笑声] 对不起，我需要在这里绑定
events 事件。 好的，现在这样
我们就可以编辑它了，运行正常。
这个 class 组件我们应该非常熟悉了。你如果
使用 React 开发可能会遇到很多类似的
代码。但让我们后退一步，如果
想要使用 state 时，能否不必须使用
class 组件？我不确定
它如何运行。但是我就准备
跟据我的已知来进行，我需要渲染一个
input。我在这里放入一个 input。
这个 input 的 value 的值为
当前的 name 的值，所以我就传入
name 值。我不知道从哪里获取 name。
它不是从 props 里面来，嗯，
我就在这里声明，我不知道它的值，
之后我再填写这一块。呃，这里应该也有一个
change 回调函数，我在
这里声明 onChange 函数 handleNameChange。
我在这里添加一个函数来
处理事件。在这里我想要通知 React
设置 name 值到某处，但又一次地，
我不确定在 functional 组件里如何实现
这个功能。因此我就直接调用
一个叫做 setName 的方法。
使用当前的 input 的值。我把它
声明在这里。
好吧，由于这两件事情
是密切相关的，对吧。其中一个是 state 里
name 变量的当前值，
而另一个是一个函数，
该函数让我们去设置 state 里的 name 变量。
由于这两件事情
非常相关，我将它们
合并到一起作为一对值。
我们从某处一同获取到
它们的值。所以问题是我从哪里获取到它们？
答案是从 React 本地状态里面获取。 那么我如何
在 function 组件里面获取到 React 到本地状态呢？
嗯，我直接使用 use state
会怎样。
把初始到状态传给 useState 函数来指定它的初始值。
我们来看一下程序运行是否正常。是的，运行正常。
[掌声和欢呼声]
So let's, let's compare the two
approaches. So on the left we have a
familiar class component. This state has
to be an object. Uh, we bind some event
handlers so that we can access. This
inside the event handler for this dot setState.
When we call setState it
actually doesn't just set the state that
merges, the state are the argument into
the state object. And then when we want
to access the state which is this dot
state dot something. So in the
example on the right, we don't need to
access this dot state dot something.
Because the name state variable is
already available in the function. It's
just the variable. And similarly when we
need to set the state, we don't need to
access this dot something. Because the
function that let us set the name is
also available in the scope. So what is
useState exactly? UseState is a hook. A
hook is a function provided by React
that lets you hook into React features
from your function components. And
useState is the first hook that we're going
to take a look at today, but there are a
few more. So we're going to see them
later.
All right, so let's go back to our
familiar class example. So let's say we
wanted to add a second field. For example,
for a surname. So the way we normally do
this is we add another key to the state.
And we, uh, I'm going to copy and paste this
row. It's gonna say surname now. It's
going to render a surname, and handleSurnameChange.
When I copy and paste
this event handler, this will be surname.
And I need to bind it.
Okay, Mary Poppins. So we can see that it
works. Uh, so how do we do the same with
hooks? So one thing we could do is we
could make our state an object. As you
can see that the state with hooks state
doesn't have to be an object. It can be
any primitive. We could make it an object
if we wanted to, but we also don't have
to. So conceptually surname is, uh, is not
closely related to state, uh, to the name. So
what we could do is we could declare a
second state variable by calling the
useState hook again.
So I'll declare surname. I can give it any
name, it's just the variable in my code.
And setSurname. Calling useState and
passing the initial state for that state
variable 'Poppins'.
So again I'm gonna copy and paste
the row. Say surname, the value surname,
handleSurnameChange. And when the user
edits the surname, not sir name, we want
to set the surname.
Let's see if this works.
Yay, it looks like it works. [Applause]
So we can see that we can use hooks more
than once in a component. Let's compare
the two approaches in more detail. So on
the left familiar class component state
is always an object, has multiple fields,
may call setState will merge some
something into that object. And then when
we want to access it, we do this dot
state dot something. On the right in the
example using hooks, we use the state
hook twice. And that declares two state
variables: name and surname. And whenever
we call setName or setSurname,
this tells React that it needs to
rerender this component, just like if we
called setState. And so the next time
React renders our components is going
to pass the current name and the current
surname to our component. And then we can
use it directly without accessing this
dot state dot something.
All right. So let's go back to our class
example. What else, what other features of
React we know? So another thing you
might want to do from a component is to
read context. So context, in case you're
not familiar, it's like, ur, kind of like
global variables for a subtree. So it's
useful for things like read the current
theme like visual theme or the current
language that the user is using. And it's
useful to avoid passing everything
through props if you need all components
to be able to read some value. So we're
going to import ThemeContext and
LocaleContext which I already declared in
another file. And the API you've probably
most familiar with for consuming context,
especially if you have to consume
multiple contexts, is the render prop API.
And it looks like this. So I'm going to
scroll down here. So we can choose ThemeContext
Consumer that gives us the theme.
In my case, it's just going to be a CSS
class. So I copy this, all this code
inside the render prop. And I'm going to
use className equals 'theme' . All right,
very old-timey. [Laughing]
And I also want to show the current
language, so I'm going to use
LocaleContext Consumer. And it's going to
render another row, so I will copy and
paste this row, can say language.
Language. And render it here. Okay, we can
see that context works. And that's
probably normally consume context. We
actually added a more convenient API for
accessing it in classes in 16.6. Ur, but
this is how you can see multiple
contexts. So let's look at the, at how we
could do this with hooks. So as we said
that, state is a fundamental feature of
React and this is why you can use state.
And so if we want to use context, I need
to import my contexts. So this is gonna
be a ThemeContext, LocaleContext. And
now if I want to use context from my
component, I can use context. And then to
get the current theme, I can use context
ThemeContext. And to get the current
locale I can use context LocaleContext.
And this doesn't just read the context,
it also subscribes the component to
updates to this context. But it just
gives me the current values, so I can, I
can put it into my CSS className. And I
can add the bro, that's language, and I can
put it here.
[Applause]
All right, so let's,let's compare the two
approaches. So this is the traditional
kind of render prop API.
It is very explicit about what it's
doing. But it does get a little bit
nested and you encounter this not just
with context with, with any kind of
render prop API. So with hooks, it
does the same thing. But it's flat. So we
just say we use this context in this
context and we get the theme and locale.
And then we can use them. So you might be
wondering at this point how can React
possibly know. For example, I have this two
useState calls. So how does it know
which state variable corresponds to
which useState call. And the answer is
that React relies on the order of these
calls. This may be a little bit unusual.
And, ah, in order for this to work correctly,
there is a rule that you need to follow
when you use hooks. And the rule is that
you cannot call hook inside a condition.
It has to be at the top level of your
component. So if I do something like, if
props condition, and then I call the useState
hook here. We actually have a
linter plugin that is going to complain
that 'This is not the correct way to use
hooks'. And we realize that this is an
unusual limitation, uh, but it is pretty
important for hooks tour correctly and
also to enable certain things that I
think will you will like that I will show
it later.
All right, so let's go back to our class.
So the other thing you might want to
reach for the class for is lifecycle
methods. So the most commonly use case
for lifecycle methods is you want to
perform some side effect such as firing
off request, performing some kind of
imperative DOM mutation interfacing with
the browser APIs. So you might want to
do something like this and you can't do
during rendering, because it's, it's not
rendered yet. So the way you do
side effects in React is you declare a
lifecycle method like componentDidMount.
And then let's say that, uh, if, let me show
this. So you see at the top of the screen,
it says React App. So there is actually a
browser API that lets us update this. So
let's say we want the tab title to be
the name of the person and changed it as
I type. And so to set it initially I'm
going, uh, there is a browser API to do
this, is document.title equals
this.state.name plus space plus
this.state.surname. So now we can
see it says Mary Poppins. But then if I,
if I edit it, it doesn't get
automatically updated, because I also
need to implement componentDitUpdate.
For the, uh, for the side effects to be
consistent with what I rendered. So I'm
going to declare componentDitUpdate,
and just copy and paste this.
All right, so now says Mary Poppins, but if I
started editing it, the document title
updates. And this is how we perform side
effects in a class.
So how do we do this with hooks. Well the
ability to perform side effects is
another core feature of React components.
So if we want to use an effect from our
component. Make an import use effect from
React. And then we want to tell React
what to do after React has flushed our
components to the DOM. So we pass a
function which is where we perform our
effect. So I'm going to say document dot
title equals name plus space plus
surname. You can see it says Mary Poppins
here. And if I start editing it actually
updates.
So what default useEffect runs both
after the initial render and after every
update. So by default it is consistent
with what here rendered. And you can opt
out of this behavior if like for
performance reasons and, or if you have
special logic. And Ryan's talk after me
will touch a little bit on this. So let's
compare the two approaches. So in the, in the
class we divide method ... we divide the
logic based on lifecycle method names. So
this is why we have componentDidMount,
componentDitUpdate, they fire at
different times. And we sometimes repeat
some logic between them, we could extract
it to a function but still we would have
to call it in two places and remember to
keep it consistent. And with, uh, with the
effect hook, the effects are consistent
by default although there is a way to
opt out of that. And not is that in the
class we need to access this dot state,
so there needs to be a special API to do
this. But in the effect example, we
actually don't need a special API to
access the state
variable. Because it's already in the
scope of the function. It is declared
right above. And this is why the effect
is declared inside the component rather
than the, rather than outside. Because
this gives us access to state variables,
ability to set them and anything else
like the current context value for
example, or any of these contexts.
All right, so let's go back to the familiar
class example. Ur, another thing you might
want to use lifecycle methods for in a
class is subscriptions. So maybe you want
to subscribe to some kind of browser API
and it gives you some value, for example
the window size. And you want to update
the state in response to changes to this
value. And so the way we could do this in
a class, let's say that we want to, ur, that
we want to monitor the window width. So
I'm going to put width into state. This
window innerWidth browser API. And I
want to render it. Ur, let me copy and paste
this. So this is gonna say width. And I'm
going to render it here. It is this dot state
dot width. This is the width of the
window, not the width of Mary Poppins. [Laughing]
And I'm going to add a, ur, I'm going to add
an event listener, so we need to actually
listen to changes in the width. So at
window dot addEventListener.
I'm, I'm going to listen to the resize
event, handle resize. And I need to
declare this event. And so this is where
we're going to update the width state, to
be window dot innerWidth. And we need
to bind it. And, uh, and I also need to
unsubscribe. So I don't want a memory
leak with like keeping these
subscriptions. I want to unsubscribe from
this event. So the way we do this in a
class is we create another lifecycle
method called componentWillUnmount. And
I'm going to copy and paste this logic
here, except this will
removeEventListener. So we set up an event
listener, and we remove the event
listener. And we can verify that this
actually works by dragging this. You see
the width is changing. So it works. So
let's see how could ...  how we could do this
with hooks. So conceptually listening to
the window width has nothing to do with
setting the document title. So that's why
we're not gonna put it in that effect.
It's conceptually completely separate
effect and just like we could use state
more than once to declare multiple state
variables, we can use effect more than
once to perform different side effects.
So I want to subscribe to window
addEventListener, resize, handleResize. And
I'm gonna need to keep some state for
the current width.
So I'm actually going to declare another
state variable. So I'll say, ur, width and
setWidth. We get them by using state with
window innerWidth as the initial value.
And now in my handleResize function,
I'll just declare it here. Because it
isn't used anywhere else. And it's going
to setWidth to the current width. Um, I
need to render it. So I'll copy
and paste this row. I'm gonna say width.
And finally I need to clean up after
this effect. So I need to specify how to
clean up. And again conceptually cleaning
up is part of this effect. So this effect
has a clean up place. And the order, you,
the way you can specify it is that any
effect can optionally return a function.
And if it does return the function, then
React will call this function to clean
up after the effect. So this is where we
unsubscribe.
Okay, let's just verify that this
actually works. Yay. [Applause]
So let's compare the two approaches. On the left, we have a
familiar class component, ur, nothing
surprising there. We, we have some side
effects, some related logic is split
apart. So we can see that document title
has been set here. But it's also being
set here. And then we subscribe to an
effect here.
Sorry, subscribe to the event here, but we
unsubscribe here. So these things need to
be in sync with each other. And then this
method contains two unrelated methods
two unrelated lines. So that me in the in
feature make it a bit difficult to test
them in isolation. But it looks very
familiar. So that's, that's nice. So this
code probably looks less familiar. But
let's take another look at what's going
on here. Ur, in with hooks we separate code
not based on the lifecycle method name,
but based on what the code is doing. So
we can see that there is one effect
which is we updated document title.
That's one thing, this component can do.
And then there is another effect which
is subscribing to the window resize
event and update in the state when it
changes. And, ur, this effect has a cleanup
phase which means that when it's time to
remove this effect React removes it and
avoids the memory leaks. And if you've
been carefully watching, you might notice
that since effect run after every render,
we're just gonna keep resubscribing. So
there is a way to optimize this. Uh, so
default is to be consistent, ur, which is
important. If you for example use some
prop here, I need to resubscribe to a different id from
props or something similar. But there is
a way to optimize it and opt out of this
behavior. And Ryan in the next
talk will mention how to do it.
All right, so there is one more thing that I want
to show here. So this component is
getting pretty large, and it's fine. So we
expect that since you now can do more in
function components, they will get larger
and that's totally okay. Um, but you might
want to reuse some of that logic in
other components or extract it or test
it separately. What's interesting though
is that hooks calls uh, they are just
function calls. And components they are
just functions. So how do you share your
logic between two functions? You extract
it to a different function. That's what
I'm going to do. You're going to copy and
paste this. And I'm going to create a new
function called useWindowWidth and I'll
just paste it here. And so we need the
width in our component in order to
render it. So I need to return it from
this function, which is the current width.
And then I can go back up. And I can say
const width equals useWindowWidth.
[Applause]
[Cheers]
So what is this function? We didn't do
anything special, we just extracted the
function. Uh, but there is a convention here.
So we are calling this function a custom
hook. And by convention custom hook names
always start with use. And so there are
two reasons for this. We're now going to
like read your function name or to
string it or anything like this. But it
is an important convention because first
of all, this lets us lint automatically
for violation of the first rule that I
described about call hooks unconditionally.
So if we didn't know if something is a
hook, then we wouldn't be able to do that.
And another reason is that if you just
look at the component code, you kind of
want to know if some function can have
some state inside of it. So it's
important that there is a convention is
, okay, use something it means that it's
potentially stateful. And here width gives
us the current width and subscribes us to
updates through it. So if we wanted to, we
could even go further. It's probably not
necessary in this example, but I just
want to give you like a sense of what
you could do. Um, so let's say like maybe
setting the document title was a bit
more complicated and you wanted to like
extract it or test it separately. So I
could just copy and paste this. and I
could write a new custom hook. I'm gonna
call this one useDocumentTitle. And so
the name and surname don't really make
sense in the scope's context. We just want
to call this title. And this is going to
be an argument, so custom hooks are
javascript functions, so they can take
arguments and return values or not
return. So it is going to take title as
an argument. And now in my component, I
can say useDocumentTitle, name plus
surname.
In fact, I could go even further. So in
this case it's totally unnecessary, but
again, maybe our inputs were more
complicated, maybe we were tracking
whether the input was focused and
blurred, whether it has been validated,
submitted and so on. So maybe we had some
more logic there we wanted to pull it
out of our components. Um, and reduce
duplication. And there is already some
duplication, so we have this like almost
identical event handlers. So what if we
could just, um, I'm going to delete one of
them and extract the other one. I'm going
to create a new hook, that I'm going to
call useFormInput. So this is my change
handler. Now I'll also copy and paste
this declaration. So this defines the
state for this input. And so it's no
longer name and setName. I'll just call
generically value and setValue. It's
going to take the initial value as an
argument. And this is just going to be a
handleChange, and this will setValue. So
what do we want to get in order to use
this, uh, use an input in our component? We
want to get the current value, and a
change handler. These are the things that
we attach to the input. So let's just
return them. Um, return value and onChange
handleChange. So now if we go back up, we
can say name equals useFormInput Mary.
The name is going to be an object with
value and onChange fields. And surname
is useFormInput Poppins. So this is now
going to be named dot value and surname
dot value because this is where the
string is. And so now I can remove this,
and I can spread over the name object.
Someone is laughing. [Laughing] All right. Let's just
verify it and break it, yeah it works. So
each time we call a hook, its state is
completely isolated. And this is because
we just rely on the order of hook calls,
and not on names or anything. So you can
call the same hook multiple times. Each
call will get its own local state. So
let's compare the two approaches for
the last time. Um, so on the left we have a
familiar class component, it has some,
some state in an object, bind some
methods, has some logic spread across
different lifecycle methods as a
bunch of event handlers, um, uses, um, uses
something things from the context and
render stuff. Um, pretty familiar. And on the
right pane, this may not look like the
React components were used to. But it
kind of makes sense. Even if you don't
know how these functions are implemented.
You can see okay it uses to form inputs,
uses some context to get theme and
locale, it uses the window width and
document title, and it renders a bunch of
stuff. And if we want to. We can scroll
further and we can see okay, so this is
how the input works, this is how setting
the document title works, this is how the
window width subscription works. Or maybe
this could be an npm package and you
don't actually need to know that. All we
could pull it back into a component or
copy and paste between components. So
hooks give you custom hooks, give you the
flexibility to create your own
abstractions that are not ...  they do not
inflate your React component tree and avoid
the wrapper hell.
[Applause]
And importantly these are not two
separate applications. So this is
actually one application. So I have this
window open just to demonstrate that
classes can work side by side with hooks.
And while hooks represent our vision for
the future of React. Uh, we don't want to
make breaking changes like this. So we
need to keep classes working. Ur, let's go
back to you the slides. All right, now
this is a slider you can actually tweet. [Laughing]
We present the Hooks proposal to you
today.
Uh, hooks let us to use all React features
without having to write a class. They do
not deprecated classes, but you have the
option to not have to write them. We
intend to cover all use cases for
classes with hooks as soon as possible.
There are a few that are missing, but
we're working on them. And hooks let you
reuse stateful logic, extracted out of
components, tested separately, reuse it
between different components without
introducing the wrapper hell. And again
importantly it's not a breaking change,
completely backwards compatible, strictly
addition ..., uh, additive. And you can find the,
we wrote the documentation for hooks, so
you can find it at this url. Um, and
we want to hear from you, the React
community wanna hear what you think
about hooks. Um, whether you like them or not.
And we realize that it's pretty hard to
give feedback without actually trying
them. So we built them, and we released
sixty ..., um, sixteen seven alpha. It's not a
major release, it's a minor release. But
in alpha where you can try hooks. And
we've been trying them in production at
Facebook for about a month. So we don't
expect major bugs there. But the APIs
themselves may change together with your
feedback. And I asked you not to rewrite
anything like not to rewrite their whole
apps with hooks. Because first of all it's,
it's a proposal. And second because
personally I, I find that it takes a bit
of a mind shift to start thinking in
hooks, and it might be a bit confusing if
you try to just take a class component
and convert it. But I do encourage you to
try using hooks in some of the newer
code that you write in and let us know
what you think. So,
thank you.
[Applause]
So in our view hooks represent our
vision for the future of React. But I
think they also represent the way we
move React forward. And that is we don't
do big rewrite. Uh, we want the new patterns
that we like better to coexist with the
old patterns, so that we can have gradual
migration and adoption just like you can
gradually adopt React itself. And this is
almost the end of my talk. Uh, I want to end
it on a personal note. So I started
learning React about four years ago. And
one of my first questions was why JSX.
Uh, but my second one of the next questions
was I can figure out what does the logo
have to do with React. So the project is
not called Atom, it's not a physics
engine.
Um, so one interpretation is that it's kind
of upon on
reactions, so atoms participate in
chemical reactions, reactions -> React. Um, but
it's not a claim with React actually
got it, uh, I found a different interpretation
that made more sense to me. And the way I
think about it, uh,
we know that physical matter consists of
atoms. And we've learned that it's the
types of these atoms and their
properties that determine how the
physical matter looks and behaves. And
React has taught me something similar,
that you can take a user interface and
you can split it into these independent
units called components, and it's the
types and properties of these components
that can describe how the user interface
looks and behaves.
What's ironic though is that the word
'atom', it literally means indivisible. So
when scientists just discovered atom for
the first time, they thought this is the
smallest thing we're gonna find. But
later they discovered an electron, which
is a smaller particle inside the atom.
And it turned out it actually electrons
explain a lot about how atoms work. And I
kind of feel the same way about hooks. I
don't feel like hooks are a new feature.
Rather I feel that hooks provide me with
access to React features that I already
know, such as state and context and lifecycle.
And I feel like hooks are a more
direct representation of React. And that
they really explain how a component
works inside. And I feel like they've
been hiding in plain sight for four
years. And in fact if you look at the
React logo, you can see those electron
orbits there. So maybe hooks have been
there all along. Thank you.
[Applause]
Dan, thank you so much. Sophie thank you
as well.